<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com</link>
    <description>Don&#39;t be a Noob</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:01:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://azure-noob.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Admin Starter Kit (Free Download)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Download the Azure Admin Starter Kit: KQL cheat sheet, Windows/Linux command guides, and an Azure RACI template.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>50 Linux Commands for Azure (However You Deploy)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-linux-commands-azure</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-linux-commands-azure</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[The essential Linux commands every Azure administrator needs—whether you use the Portal, PowerShell, or IaC. Includes Active Directory domain join for enterprise environments.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>50 Windows Commands for Azure VMs (PowerShell + Active Directory)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-windows-commands-azure</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-windows-commands-azure</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[The essential Windows commands every Azure administrator needs—from PowerShell basics to Active Directory domain join and Group Policy troubleshooting in enterprise environments.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Cost Optimization: What Actually Works (Not Azure Advisor Recommendations)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-optimization-what-actually-works</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-optimization-what-actually-works</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Advisor says &#39;right-size your VMs.&#39; Finance says &#39;why is our cloud bill still increasing?&#39; Here&#39;s what actually reduces Azure costs in production: the tactics that work when reserved instances and Advisor recommendations aren&#39;t enough.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Azure Role Microsoft Forgot to Certify: Why There&#39;s No Exam for Workbooks, KQL, Power BI, and AI</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-reporting-role-microsoft-should-create</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-reporting-role-microsoft-should-create</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft certifies Azure Administrators, Developers, and Data Engineers. But there&#39;s no certification for the role 80% of Azure admins actually perform: building Workbooks, writing KQL queries, creating Power BI dashboards, and leveraging AI for operations. Here&#39;s the exam that should exist.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Arc Ghost Registrations: Why 64% of My Arc Inventory Doesn&#39;t Exist</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[How Azure Arc ghost registrations happen, why they wreck governance reporting, and how to detect and clean them up at scale.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Portal vs CLI vs PowerShell vs Bicep vs Terraform: Which One Should a Noob Learn First?</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Every Azure tutorial tells you what these tools do. Nobody honestly tells you which one to learn first and why. Here&#39;s the truth: start with Portal, move to CLI, then pick Bicep or Terraform. Ignore the evangelists.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Will AI Replace Azure Administrators by 2030? An Honest Assessment from the Trenches</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Everyone&#39;s talking about AI replacing jobs, but nobody&#39;s written the Azure admin-specific version. Here&#39;s what happens when the person managing 40+ subscriptions explores the AI tools that might eliminate their role.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>MCP vs Power BI AI: What Actually Creates Your Dashboards? (And What&#39;s Just Marketing)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[A practical comparison of MCP vs Power BI AI: what actually reads data, what actually builds visuals, and how Azure admins should think about both.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Tagging Best Practices: The $2.3M Tag Mess (247 Variations of One Tag)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[One tag key. 247 different spellings. $2.3M in cost allocation failures. Real lessons from enterprise Azure tag governance: why Azure Policy isn&#39;t enough and the automation that finally stopped tag chaos across 31,000 resources.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Building an Azure Arc Lab with Private Link (No Public IPs)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[A private Azure Arc lab design that lets you learn governance patterns, vCenter onboarding, and policy testing without touching production.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure OpenAI Pricing: The Real Costs Nobody Shows You</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure OpenAI usage looks cheap—until it doesn&#39;t. A real breakdown of hidden costs and how to prevent runaway AI spending in Azure.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Deploying Azure AI Foundry RAG with Terraform: Production-Ready Infrastructure as Code</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[YouTube tutorials use Azure Portal clickops. Enterprises need repeatable, secure, version-controlled deployments. Here&#39;s the complete Terraform configuration for Azure AI Foundry RAG that actually works in production - with security, monitoring, and cost controls built in.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Azure Arc Multi-vCenter Implementation Guide That Actually Works</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[End-to-end implementation guide for connecting VMware vCenter to Azure Arc with governance in mind: tags, policy, RBAC, and reporting from day one.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The 100,000 Tag Problem in Enterprise Azure</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[What happens when an enterprise ends up with 100,000+ tag variations, why it happens in the real world, and how to systematically clean it up without breaking production.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>SQL Server 2025 Vector Database: What Microsoft Doesn&#39;t Tell You About Production Deployments</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sql-server-2025-vector-database-production-reality</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sql-server-2025-vector-database-production-reality</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft integrated vector databases into SQL Server 2025. The docs show you how to enable it. They don&#39;t show you what happens when you store 10 million vectors, run 100K queries per day, or why your $500/month SQL Server becomes $3,000/month.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure AI Foundry RAG: The Enterprise Reality Check Nobody Gives You</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-rag-enterprise-reality</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-rag-enterprise-reality</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[YouTube tutorials show you how to build RAG with Azure AI Foundry in 20 minutes. They don&#39;t show you the $3,000/year cost, the production failures, or when you shouldn&#39;t use it at all. Here&#39;s what happens when you actually deploy this at scale.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>CVE-2025-49752: Critical Azure Bastion Vulnerability - What You Need to Know Right Now</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cve-2025-49752-azure-bastion-vulnerability</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cve-2025-49752-azure-bastion-vulnerability</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[CVSS 10.0 authentication bypass in Azure Bastion lets attackers escalate to admin without credentials. Microsoft patched it November 20th. Here&#39;s what Azure admins need to do immediately.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How I Rebranded Microsoft&#39;s Azure Resource Inventory Dashboard (Without Corrupting Excel)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboard-rebranding-tool</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboard-rebranding-tool</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[A dark-mode rebranding tool for Azure dashboards and Excel exports so your reports look as modern as your cloud environment.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Why I Open-Sourced My Enterprise Azure Operations Repository</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/open-source-enterprise-azure-ops</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/open-source-enterprise-azure-ops</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft tells you how to create Azure resources. I&#39;m documenting how to actually operate them at enterprise scale. Here&#39;s why I&#39;m sharing operational knowledge that most architects keep private, and how AI helped me build portable intellectual property.]]></description>
    </item>
    
</channel>
</rss>