<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com</link>
    <description>Don&#39;t be a Noob</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:56:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://azure-noob.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
        <title>The 23 Azure Services You Actually Need to Know (Out of 200+)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/23-azure-services-you-need</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/23-azure-services-you-need</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure lists 200+ services. You only need to deeply understand 23 of them. These services appear in every enterprise environment from 20 VMs to 30,000 resources. Master these first—ignore the other 180 until you actually need them.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Chargeback Architecture: The Two Models That Actually Work</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-architecture-reality</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-architecture-reality</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure chargeback requires architecture-first design: subscription-per-application (clean isolation) or subscription-per-department (tag discipline required). Tags alone won&#39;t fix bad architecture. True chargeback happens in your ERP, not Azure Cost Management.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Terraform Modules for Azure: From Local to Published (4 Steps That Actually Work)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/terraform-modules-azure-from-local-to-published</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/terraform-modules-azure-from-local-to-published</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Stop copy-pasting Terraform code across repos. Build reusable modules, version them properly, and publish to Azure DevOps Artifacts or Terraform Registry.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>What the CAF Won&#39;t Tell You About Azure Subscriptions (And Why Azure Arc Makes It Worse)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/what-caf-wont-tell-you-azure-subscriptions-arc</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/what-caf-wont-tell-you-azure-subscriptions-arc</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft&#39;s Cloud Adoption Framework teaches subscriptions as a scale unit. In regulated enterprises, subscriptions are security boundaries. That&#39;s not an advanced topic—it&#39;s the foundation. Azure Arc amplifies this problem by extending broken subscription models to on-prem infrastructure.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Policy Reality Check: Why Your Guardrails Fail After 30 Days</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Policy is powerful on paper, but in enterprise environments the guardrails collapse almost immediately. Here&#39;s why your policies stop working and what it takes to build a policy framework that survives production.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Arc at Enterprise Scale: The Problems Microsoft Doesn&#39;t Document</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-enterprise-scale-problems</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-enterprise-scale-problems</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Arc demos show 5-10 servers connecting perfectly. Enterprise deployments with hundreds of on-premises and VMware servers look different. Here&#39;s what actually breaks at scale - ghost registrations, network complexity, vCenter integration, and the operational reality Microsoft&#39;s documentation doesn&#39;t prepare you for.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Building a Persistent Azure Operations Dashboard (AZQR + App Service + Storage)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azqr-persistent-dashboard</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azqr-persistent-dashboard</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft&#39;s Azure Quick Review (AZQR) consolidates Advisor, Defender for Cloud, Policy, and Cost Management into one dashboard - but only runs locally. Here&#39;s how to host it in Azure App Service for 24/7 team access, scheduled scans, and historical tracking. Complete with Dockerfile, deployment scripts, and Entra ID authentication. Part 3 of the Azure Operations Platform series.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Operational Intelligence: Using Azure Tags for Instant Answers (2025)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tags-operational-intelligence</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tags-operational-intelligence</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure tags evolved from preventing Azure Update Manager disasters to becoming our operational intelligence layer. The Type tag excludes appliances from automated patching while enabling instant answers to executive questions about on-prem footprint, vendor inventory, and migration progress. Policy enforcement in Deny mode, tag-based filtering workflows, and KQL queries that answer &#39;how many machines on-prem?&#39; in 30 seconds instead of manual 3-day inventory projects.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Lie Azure Cost Management Tells Enterprises in 2025</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-management-lie</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-management-lie</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Cost Management works beautifully—if you have perfect subscriptions or perfect tags. At enterprise scale, you have neither. Here&#39;s why Microsoft&#39;s cost tooling assumes a reality that doesn&#39;t exist, and what actually works when you&#39;re managing 40+ subscriptions with legacy chaos, M&amp;A artifacts, and shared services everywhere.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Napkin Test: Why 90% of Azure Governance Fails at the Executive Level</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Policy enforces rules. Landing Zones provide structure. Tags enable reporting. But if you can&#39;t explain your Azure bill on a napkin, none of it matters. Here&#39;s why governance fails—and what defensibility actually requires.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Migrate&#39;s 18-Month Data Deletion: The Enterprise Migration Timer Microsoft Calls &#39;Expected Behavior&#39;</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-certificate-18-month-limit</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-certificate-18-month-limit</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Migrate appliances have an 18-month hard limit before mandatory re-registration that deletes all discovery data. Microsoft documents this as &#39;expected behavior&#39; in the FAQ but provides no alerts, no data preservation, and no migration path. The certificate expires at 12 months with one 6-month extension available, then forces complete appliance reconfiguration with total data loss at month 18.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Why Azure Subscriptions Are Both a Security Boundary and a Billing One (And Why That Breaks Everything)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-subscriptions-security-billing-boundary</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-subscriptions-security-billing-boundary</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft documents subscriptions as security boundaries. Finance treats them as cost centers. Nobody tells you they&#39;re both—and that this dual nature is why your Azure governance keeps failing. Here&#39;s the architectural decision that determines whether your costs will ever be defensible.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Logic App That Monitors Every Expiring Certificate in Azure (And Accidentally Saved Our Migration)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/logic-app-certificate-monitor</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/logic-app-certificate-monitor</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Production Logic App that monitors app registration certificates and secrets via Microsoft Graph API. Handles pagination for 100+ apps, extracts owner information, sends HTML email alerts. Built for security compliance, caught Azure Migrate appliances expiring before production migration. Complete walkthrough with working code.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Why Azure Tags Fail at Scale (And How to Fix It in 2025)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/why-azure-tags-fail-at-scale</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/why-azure-tags-fail-at-scale</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Tags work beautifully at 100 resources. At 10,000 resources, they&#39;re a source of organizational fiction. Here&#39;s why tag-based governance always collapses—not because people are careless, but because tags require human perfection that doesn&#39;t exist at enterprise scale.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Policy Doesn&#39;t Fix Bad Architecture (Microsoft Pretends It Does)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-doesnt-fix-bad-architecture</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-doesnt-fix-bad-architecture</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Policy enforces rules at scale - but it can&#39;t tell you if your subscriptions make sense, if your tags are lies, or why your $2M Azure bill is indefensible. Policy is a guardrail, not a steering wheel.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Landing Zone Reality Check: Why Most Enterprises Drift in 90 Days</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-landing-zone-reality-check</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-landing-zone-reality-check</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Landing Zones look perfect in Microsoft&#39;s diagrams — but drift is inevitable. Here&#39;s why they fail (organizational reasons, not technical) and what must be included for Landing Zones to survive enterprise reality.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Hybrid Benefit Audit Guide: Avoid the $50K Licensing Mistake (2025)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-hybrid-benefit-complete</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-hybrid-benefit-complete</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Hybrid Benefit saves money when used correctly - but misuse triggers $50K+ compliance penalties. This is the complete operational guide for Azure administrators: pre-migration validation, audit timelines, documentation requirements, and the 8-question checklist that prevents licensing disasters.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure FinOps 2025: The 31,000 Resource Guide to Cost Accountability</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-finops-complete-guide</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-finops-complete-guide</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure FinOps guide for 31,000+ resource environments: tag governance that survives 18 months, chargeback models business units accept, and cost visibility at application level (not subscription). Includes real banking industry implementation.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>☁️ Enterprise Migration Reality - Complete Azure Migration Guide</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/migration-hub</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/migration-hub</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Complete enterprise Azure migration hub - Pre-migration planning, licensing compliance, ROI reality checks, and lessons learned from real-world migrations at scale.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Admin Starter Kit (Free Download)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Get everything you need to start managing Azure effectively: KQL cheat sheet, 50 Windows + 50 Linux commands, and an Azure RACI template. Free, no email required.]]></description>
    </item>
    
</channel>
</rss>