<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com</link>
    <description>Don&#39;t be a Noob</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:35:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://azure-noob.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
        <title>Building an Azure Arc Lab with Private Link (No Public IPs)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Deploy a production-realistic Azure Arc demo environment using Private Link for secure hybrid management. Complete Terraform code included - because your CISO won&#39;t approve the public internet version.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>I Spent $500 Testing Azure OpenAI So You Don&#39;t Have To: The Real Costs Microsoft Doesn&#39;t Show</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft&#39;s pricing calculator shows token costs. It doesn&#39;t show the hosting fees, PTU confusion, and hidden infrastructure charges that turn a $50 pilot into a $2,000 monthly bill. Here&#39;s what actually happens when you deploy Azure OpenAI at scale.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Deploying Azure AI Foundry RAG with Terraform: Production-Ready Infrastructure as Code</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[YouTube tutorials use Azure Portal clickops. Enterprises need repeatable, secure, version-controlled deployments. Here&#39;s the complete Terraform configuration for Azure AI Foundry RAG that actually works in production - with security, monitoring, and cost controls built in.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Azure Arc Multi-vCenter Implementation Guide That Actually Works</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft pressured us to deploy Azure Arc fast. We connected 1,200+ VMs with no strategy. Here&#39;s the complete implementation guide I wish existed before we started - covering the two-phase deployment nobody explains, the tagging strategy that prevents disasters, and why calling Finance is harder than installing agents.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The $100K Problem That Resource Tags Would Have Prevented [2025 Guide]</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[How the TYPE tag plus 5 critical tags saved $113,800 on Azure Arc patching costs. Complete 2025 Azure tagging strategy with KQL queries, PowerShell scripts, and Policy enforcement.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>SQL Server 2025 Vector Database: What Microsoft Doesn&#39;t Tell You About Production Deployments</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sql-server-2025-vector-database-production-reality</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sql-server-2025-vector-database-production-reality</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft integrated vector databases into SQL Server 2025. The docs show you how to enable it. They don&#39;t show you what happens when you store 10 million vectors, run 100K queries per day, or why your $500/month SQL Server becomes $3,000/month.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure AI Foundry RAG: The Enterprise Reality Check Nobody Gives You</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-rag-enterprise-reality</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-rag-enterprise-reality</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[YouTube tutorials show you how to build RAG with Azure AI Foundry in 20 minutes. They don&#39;t show you the $3,000/year cost, the production failures, or when you shouldn&#39;t use it at all. Here&#39;s what happens when you actually deploy this at scale.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>CVE-2025-49752: Critical Azure Bastion Vulnerability - What You Need to Know Right Now</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cve-2025-49752-azure-bastion-vulnerability</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cve-2025-49752-azure-bastion-vulnerability</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[CVSS 10.0 authentication bypass in Azure Bastion lets attackers escalate to admin without credentials. Microsoft patched it November 20th. Here&#39;s what Azure admins need to do immediately.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How I Rebranded Microsoft&#39;s Azure Resource Inventory Dashboard (Without Corrupting Excel)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboard-rebranding-tool</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboard-rebranding-tool</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[PowerShell script that transforms ARI dashboards with your branding and full dark mode - zero file corruption, professional results in 30 seconds.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Why I Open-Sourced My Enterprise Azure Operations Repository</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/open-source-enterprise-azure-ops</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/open-source-enterprise-azure-ops</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft tells you how to create Azure resources. I&#39;m documenting how to actually operate them at enterprise scale. Here&#39;s why I&#39;m sharing operational knowledge that most architects keep private, and how AI helped me build portable intellectual property.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Gartner’s AI Forecast for 2030: What It Really Means for Azure Admins</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/gartner-ai-forecast-azure-admin</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/gartner-ai-forecast-azure-admin</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Gartner predicts that by 2030, 0% of IT work will be done without AI involvement. Here’s what that means for Azure administrators, cloud engineers, and anyone responsible for running enterprise cloud environments.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The AI Admin: Stop Being a Human API Wrapper</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/the-ai-admin</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/the-ai-admin</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Traditional Azure administration is becoming AI-assisted automation. Here&#39;s how to position yourself as an AI Admin instead of a human ticket processor - whether you&#39;re managing 40,000 resources or bootstrapping your first deployment.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Companies Don&#39;t Want Azure Admins Anymore. They Want People Who Can Make AI Work. (And Almost Nobody Is Teaching This)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/ai-azure-admins-gap</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/ai-azure-admins-gap</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[I searched &#39;Azure Administrator skills 2025&#39; and found hundreds of articles. Not one mentioned AI capability. Meanwhile, ChatGPT just wrote better PowerShell than half my team in 30 seconds. The gap between what&#39;s being taught and what companies need is massive.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Three AI Operations Roles That Don&#39;t Exist Yet (But Will in 12 Months)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/three-ai-roles</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/three-ai-roles</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Search for &#39;AI operations governance jobs&#39; and find nothing. Meanwhile someone has to monitor AI usage, prevent security disasters, and measure ROI. These three roles don&#39;t exist officially. They will soon.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>From Chaos to Enterprise: How I Set Up Terraform Remote State in Azure (And Why You Need This Yesterday)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/terraform-remote-state-azure</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/terraform-remote-state-azure</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[After our third &#39;who deleted the state file&#39; incident, I finally set up proper Terraform remote state. 30 minutes of work eliminated an entire category of disasters. Here&#39;s exactly how to do it, with zero fluff.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Application Migration Checklist Nobody Gave You (And Why Your Migrations Keep Failing)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/application-migration-checklist-azure</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/application-migration-checklist-azure</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft&#39;s migration docs won&#39;t tell you this: 80% of migration failures happen because you didn&#39;t ask these 8 questions BEFORE you started. Here&#39;s the checklist that actually works in enterprise environments.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Cloud Migration Strategy: The Pre-Migration Checklist That Saves Millions</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cloud-migration-reality-check</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cloud-migration-reality-check</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Before migrating to Azure: Do you know how many applications you have? This enterprise cloud migration checklist (with downloadable spreadsheet) prevents the costly mistakes most Azure migrations make. Real lessons from a 2019 migration project.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Only 1% of Azure Admins Know These Three Tools — And Even Fewer Know When to Use Which</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/only-1-percent-know-these-tools</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/only-1-percent-know-these-tools</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[I passed AZ-104. I was certified. I knew how to create VMs, configure networking, deploy ARM templates. Day 1 on the job: &#39;Pull me an inventory.&#39; AZ-104 never covered this. Here&#39;s the certification gap nobody talks about, the query that proves it, and the templates that save your career.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>I&#39;ll Pull The Meta From ARM - What 6 Months of KQL Actually Looks Like</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/pull-meta-from-arm</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/pull-meta-from-arm</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[I promised executives I&#39;d query Azure Resource Manager for &#39;the answers.&#39; They nodded. I got budget. Nobody asked what metadata actually exists in ARM. Here&#39;s the 35-line query I built to answer &#39;what VMs do we have&#39; - and the 35 more I needed for everything else.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Buzzwords, Technical Terms, and the Meetings Where Nobody Understands Anything</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/buzzwords-meetings-confusion</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/buzzwords-meetings-confusion</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Why corporate arrogance kills more cloud projects than technical complexity ever could. The uncomfortable truth about how leadership uses business buzzwords and technical teams use jargon - and nobody admits they don&#39;t understand each other.]]></description>
    </item>
    
</channel>
</rss>