<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com</link>
    <description>Don&#39;t be a Noob</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:06:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://azure-noob.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Policy Reality Check: Why Your Guardrails Fail After 30 Days</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Policy is powerful on paper, but in enterprise environments the guardrails collapse almost immediately. Here&#39;s why your policies stop working and what it takes to build a policy framework that survives production.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>You Can&#39;t Govern What You Can&#39;t Explain on a Napkin</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Policy enforces rules. Landing Zones provide structure. Tags enable reporting. But if you can&#39;t explain your Azure bill on a napkin, none of it matters. Here&#39;s why governance fails—and what defensibility actually requires.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Policy Doesn&#39;t Fix Bad Architecture (Microsoft Pretends It Does)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-doesnt-fix-bad-architecture</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-doesnt-fix-bad-architecture</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Policy enforces rules at scale - but it can&#39;t tell you if your subscriptions make sense, if your tags are lies, or why your $2M Azure bill is indefensible. Policy is a guardrail, not a steering wheel.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Landing Zone Reality Check: Why Most Enterprises Drift in 90 Days</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-landing-zone-reality-check</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-landing-zone-reality-check</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Landing Zones look perfect in Microsoft&#39;s diagrams — but drift is inevitable. Here&#39;s why they fail (organizational reasons, not technical) and what must be included for Landing Zones to survive enterprise reality.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Hybrid Benefit vs. Cloud License: The $50K Licensing Mistake Every Azure Admin Must Avoid</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-hybrid-benefit-complete</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-hybrid-benefit-complete</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Hybrid Benefit saves money when used correctly - but misuse triggers $50K+ compliance penalties. This is the complete operational guide for Azure administrators: pre-migration validation, audit timelines, documentation requirements, and the 8-question checklist that prevents licensing disasters.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure FinOps 2025: Complete Guide to Cloud Financial Operations</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-finops-complete-guide</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-finops-complete-guide</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure FinOps guide for 31,000+ resource environments: tag governance that survives 18 months, chargeback models business units accept, and cost visibility at application level (not subscription). Includes real banking industry implementation.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>☁️ Enterprise Migration Reality - Complete Azure Migration Guide</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/migration-hub</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/migration-hub</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Complete enterprise Azure migration hub - Pre-migration planning, licensing compliance, ROI reality checks, and lessons learned from real-world migrations at scale.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Admin Starter Kit (Free Download)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Get everything you need to start managing Azure effectively: KQL cheat sheet, 50 Windows + 50 Linux commands, and an Azure RACI template. Free, no email required.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Command Finder (Interactive Tool)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-command-finder</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-command-finder</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Interactive troubleshooting tool - select your Azure problem, get the exact commands to fix it. Copy-paste ready workflows for RDP issues, domain join, Group Policy, costs, and more.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>50 Linux Commands for Azure (However You Deploy)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-linux-commands-azure</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-linux-commands-azure</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[The essential Linux commands every Azure administrator needs—whether you use the Portal, PowerShell, or IaC. Includes Active Directory domain join for enterprise environments.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>50 Windows Commands for Azure VMs (PowerShell + Active Directory)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-windows-commands-azure</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-windows-commands-azure</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[The essential Windows commands every Azure administrator needs—from PowerShell basics to Active Directory domain join and Group Policy troubleshooting in enterprise environments.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Cost Optimization: What Actually Works (Not Azure Advisor Recommendations)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-optimization-what-actually-works</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-optimization-what-actually-works</guid>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure Advisor says &#39;right-size your VMs.&#39; Finance says &#39;why is our cloud bill still increasing?&#39; Here&#39;s what actually reduces Azure costs in production: the tactics that work when reserved instances and Advisor recommendations aren&#39;t enough.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Azure Role Microsoft Forgot to Certify: Why There&#39;s No Exam for Workbooks, KQL, Power BI, and AI</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-reporting-role-microsoft-should-create</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-reporting-role-microsoft-should-create</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Microsoft certifies Azure Administrators, Developers, and Data Engineers. But there&#39;s no certification for the role 80% of Azure admins actually perform: building Workbooks, writing KQL queries, creating Power BI dashboards, and leveraging AI for operations. Here&#39;s the exam that should exist.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Arc Ghost Registrations: Why 64% of My Arc Inventory Doesn&#39;t Exist</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</guid>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[How Azure Arc ghost registrations happen, why they wreck governance reporting, and how to detect and clean them up at scale.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Portal vs CLI vs PowerShell vs Bicep vs Terraform: Which One Should a Noob Learn First?</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Every Azure tutorial tells you what these tools do. Nobody honestly tells you which one to learn first and why. Here&#39;s the truth: start with Portal, move to CLI, then pick Bicep or Terraform. Ignore the evangelists.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Will AI Replace Azure Administrators by 2030? An Honest Assessment from the Trenches</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Everyone&#39;s talking about AI replacing jobs, but nobody&#39;s written the Azure admin-specific version. Here&#39;s what happens when the person managing 40+ subscriptions explores the AI tools that might eliminate their role.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>MCP vs Power BI AI: What Actually Creates Your Dashboards? (And What&#39;s Just Marketing)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[A practical comparison of MCP vs Power BI AI: what actually reads data, what actually builds visuals, and how Azure admins should think about both.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure Tagging Best Practices: The $2.3M Tag Mess (247 Variations of One Tag)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</guid>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[One tag key. 247 different spellings. $2.3M in cost allocation failures. Real lessons from enterprise Azure tag governance: why Azure Policy isn&#39;t enough and the automation that finally stopped tag chaos across 31,000 resources.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Building an Azure Arc Lab with Private Link (No Public IPs)</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</guid>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[A private Azure Arc lab design that lets you learn governance patterns, vCenter onboarding, and policy testing without touching production.]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure OpenAI Pricing: $500 POC → $50K/Month Reality</title>
        <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</link>
        <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <description><![CDATA[Azure OpenAI pricing reality: $2 demo becomes $4,000/month in production. Complete 2025 pricing ($0.002-$0.06 per 1K tokens), hidden $1,836/mo hosting fees, token calculator, and cost optimization strategies Microsoft&#39;s calculator doesn&#39;t show.]]></description>
    </item>
    
</channel>
</rss>