<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Arc Ghost Registrations: Why 64% of My Arc Inventory Doesn't Exist</title>
      <description>How Azure Arc ghost registrations happen, why they wreck governance reporting, and how to detect and clean them up at scale.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Portal vs CLI vs PowerShell vs Bicep vs Terraform: Which One Should a Noob Learn First?</title>
      <description>Every Azure tutorial tells you what these tools do. Nobody honestly tells you which one to learn first and why. Here's the truth: start with Portal, move to CLI, then pick Bicep or Terraform. Ignore the evangelists.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will AI Replace Azure Administrators by 2030? An Honest Assessment from the Trenches</title>
      <description>Everyone's talking about AI replacing jobs, but nobody's written the Azure admin-specific version. Here's what happens when the person managing 40+ subscriptions explores the AI tools that might eliminate their role.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP vs Power BI AI: What Actually Creates Your Dashboards? (And What's Just Marketing)</title>
      <description>A practical comparison of MCP vs Power BI AI: what actually reads data, what actually builds visuals, and how Azure admins should think about both.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Tagging Best Practices: The $2.3M Tag Mess (247 Variations of One Tag)</title>
      <description>One tag key. 247 different spellings. $2.3M in cost allocation failures. Real lessons from enterprise Azure tag governance: why Azure Policy isn't enough and the automation that finally stopped tag chaos across 31,000 resources.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an Azure Arc Lab with Private Link (No Public IPs)</title>
      <description>A private Azure Arc lab design that lets you learn governance patterns, vCenter onboarding, and policy testing without touching production.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI Pricing: The Real Costs Nobody Shows You</title>
      <description>Azure OpenAI usage looks cheap—until it doesn't. A real breakdown of hidden costs and how to prevent runaway AI spending in Azure.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Azure AI Foundry RAG with Terraform: Production-Ready Infrastructure as Code</title>
      <description>YouTube tutorials use Azure Portal clickops. Enterprises need repeatable, secure, version-controlled deployments. Here's the complete Terraform configuration for Azure AI Foundry RAG that actually works in production - with security, monitoring, and cost controls built in.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Azure Arc Multi-vCenter Implementation Guide That Actually Works</title>
      <description>End-to-end implementation guide for connecting VMware vCenter to Azure Arc with governance in mind: tags, policy, RBAC, and reporting from day one.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 100,000 Tag Problem in Enterprise Azure</title>
      <description>What happens when an enterprise ends up with 100,000+ tag variations, why it happens in the real world, and how to systematically clean it up without breaking production.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>