<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Icons Reference - All 284 Icons Searchable</title>
      <description>Complete searchable reference of all Azure service icons with descriptions. Stop hunting through Microsoft's icon sets - everything in one Excel file.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-icons-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-icons-reference/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Scraped the Azure Periodic Table to Build a Service Dictionary (And You Can Use It)</title>
      <description>The Azure Periodic Table is beautiful but not programmatically useful. So I scraped 200+ services into a PowerShell dictionary. Now my inventory tool shows service descriptions, naming conventions, and cost tiers.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-periodic-table-service-dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-periodic-table-service-dictionary/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Service Inventory Tool: Which of the 397 Services Do You Actually Use?</title>
      <description>The Azure Periodic Table is beautiful but useless for operations. Here's a tool that tells you which services you're actually using, how many, and what they cost.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-service-inventory-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-service-inventory-tool/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Logic Apps Every Azure Admin Should Build</title>
      <description>Stop clicking buttons. These 4 Logic Apps automate the boring operational tasks that break when ignored: unused resources, certificate expiration, tag compliance, and backup verification.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/four-logic-apps-every-azure-admin-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/four-logic-apps-every-azure-admin-needs/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Collaboration Gap: What Azure Admins Need to Know About Claude vs Copilot</title>
      <description>Everyone writes about building AI solutions. Nobody writes about using AI as a daily tool. Here's the technical breakdown of two different approaches to AI-assisted Azure operations.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-collaboration-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-collaboration-gap/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop Losing Your KQL Queries: The Git-Based Query Library Nobody Told You About</title>
      <description>You've written the perfect KQL query. Three months later, you can't find it. Here's the simple Git workflow that saves me 10+ hours a month searching for queries I already wrote.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/kql-query-library-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/kql-query-library-git/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Migrated My Own Azure Virtual Desktop to Windows 11 with 512GB Disk Space</title>
      <description>How I migrated from a cramped 127GB Windows 10 AVD to a spacious 512GB Windows 11 environment - including the gotchas nobody tells you about disk partitions, authentication, and user assignments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/migrating-my-avd-win10-to-win11-512gb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/migrating-my-avd-win10-to-win11-512gb/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commenting for Continuity: Why My Code Comments Don't Look Like Yours (On Purpose)</title>
      <description>Most guides say 'comment the why, not the what.' Azure admins need more: comments that double as runbooks, audit trails, and change-board briefs.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/commenting-for-continuity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/commenting-for-continuity/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Missing SOC 2 Guide: Azure Activity Log Setup (Grill Assembly Manual Edition)</title>
      <description>Every guide says 'configure diagnostic settings.' Nobody shows you which button to click. Here's the step-by-step tutorial that actually works, written for someone who's never done this before.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/soc2-activity-log-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/soc2-activity-log-step-by-step/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOC 2 Audit Prep Part 2: Azure AD Audit Log Retention Setup (Step-by-Step)</title>
      <description>The grill assembly manual for capturing Azure AD audit logs - app registrations, consent grants, sign-ins, and role assignments. Every click, every command, every verification. Part 2 of fixing the 90-day audit gap.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/soc2-azure-ad-audit-logs-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/soc2-azure-ad-audit-logs-step-by-step/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>