<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Building an Azure Arc Lab with Private Link (No Public IPs)</title>
      <description>Deploy a production-realistic Azure Arc demo environment using Private Link for secure hybrid management. Complete Terraform code included - because your CISO won't approve the public internet version.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI Pricing 2025: Real Costs After Spending $500 on Testing</title>
      <description>Real Azure OpenAI pricing breakdown: GPT-4 costs $0.03/1K tokens but hidden hosting fees ($1,224/month), PTU pricing, and infrastructure charges turn $50 pilots into $2,000 monthly bills. Actual cost data from testing across 44 Azure subscriptions.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Azure AI Foundry RAG with Terraform: Production-Ready Infrastructure as Code</title>
      <description>YouTube tutorials use Azure Portal clickops. Enterprises need repeatable, secure, version-controlled deployments. Here's the complete Terraform configuration for Azure AI Foundry RAG that actually works in production - with security, monitoring, and cost controls built in.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Azure Arc Multi-vCenter Implementation Guide That Actually Works</title>
      <description>Microsoft pressured us to deploy Azure Arc fast. We connected 1,200+ VMs with no strategy. Here's the complete implementation guide I wish existed before we started - covering the two-phase deployment nobody explains, the tagging strategy that prevents disasters, and why calling Finance is harder than installing agents.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $100K Problem That Resource Tags Would Have Prevented [2025 Guide]</title>
      <description>How the TYPE tag plus 5 critical tags saved $113,800 on Azure Arc patching costs. Complete 2025 Azure tagging strategy with KQL queries, PowerShell scripts, and Policy enforcement.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server 2025 Vector Database: What Microsoft Doesn't Tell You About Production Deployments</title>
      <description>Microsoft integrated vector databases into SQL Server 2025. The docs show you how to enable it. They don't show you what happens when you store 10 million vectors, run 100K queries per day, or why your $500/month SQL Server becomes $3,000/month.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sql-server-2025-vector-database-production-reality</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sql-server-2025-vector-database-production-reality</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure AI Foundry RAG: The Enterprise Reality Check Nobody Gives You</title>
      <description>YouTube tutorials show you how to build RAG with Azure AI Foundry in 20 minutes. They don't show you the $3,000/year cost, the production failures, or when you shouldn't use it at all. Here's what happens when you actually deploy this at scale.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-rag-enterprise-reality</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-rag-enterprise-reality</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-49752: Critical Azure Bastion Vulnerability - What You Need to Know Right Now</title>
      <description>CVSS 10.0 authentication bypass in Azure Bastion lets attackers escalate to admin without credentials. Microsoft patched it November 20th. Here's what Azure admins need to do immediately.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cve-2025-49752-azure-bastion-vulnerability</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cve-2025-49752-azure-bastion-vulnerability</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Rebranded Microsoft's Azure Resource Inventory Dashboard (Without Corrupting Excel)</title>
      <description>PowerShell script that transforms ARI dashboards with your branding and full dark mode - zero file corruption, professional results in 30 seconds.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboard-rebranding-tool</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboard-rebranding-tool</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Open-Sourced My Enterprise Azure Operations Repository</title>
      <description>Microsoft tells you how to create Azure resources. I'm documenting how to actually operate them at enterprise scale. Here's why I'm sharing operational knowledge that most architects keep private, and how AI helped me build portable intellectual property.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/open-source-enterprise-azure-ops</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/open-source-enterprise-azure-ops</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>