<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Arc Ghost Registrations: Why 64% of My Arc Inventory Doesn't Exist</title>
      <description>I reconciled Azure Arc registrations against VMware inventory and discovered 300 ghost VMs. The root cause isn't operational failure—it's architectural. Here's why Arc inventory becomes frozen in time and how Arc Resource Bridge solves it.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Portal vs CLI vs PowerShell vs Bicep vs Terraform: Which One Should a Noob Learn First?</title>
      <description>Every Azure tutorial tells you what these tools do. Nobody honestly tells you which one to learn first and why. Here's the truth: start with Portal, move to CLI, then pick Bicep or Terraform. Ignore the evangelists.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will AI Replace Azure Administrators by 2030? An Honest Assessment from the Trenches</title>
      <description>Everyone's talking about AI replacing jobs, but nobody's written the Azure admin-specific version. Here's what happens when the person managing 40+ subscriptions explores the AI tools that might eliminate their role.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP vs Power BI AI: What Actually Creates Your Dashboards? (And What's Just Marketing)</title>
      <description>Microsoft is throwing AI buzzwords everywhere. Power BI Copilot, MCP, AI-powered insights, Fabric with AI. I spent 10 weeks modernizing dashboards with AI. Here's what actually creates visuals vs what just accesses data—and why Azure admins are confused.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $2.3M Tag Mess: What Happens When 78002566 Becomes 247 Different Variations</title>
      <description>CFO asked for Azure costs by department. I found 247 different variations of the same cost center tag. 'Production' spelled 12 ways. Application names in chaos. Here's the tag governance policy that fixed it - and the template you can deploy today.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an Azure Arc Lab with Private Link (No Public IPs)</title>
      <description>Deploy a production-realistic Azure Arc demo environment using Private Link for secure hybrid management. Complete Terraform code included - because your CISO won't approve the public internet version.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI Pricing 2025: Real Costs After Spending $500 on Testing</title>
      <description>Microsoft says Azure OpenAI costs $0.03/1K tokens. Reality: Hidden $1,224/month hosting fees and infrastructure charges exploded my $50 pilot to $2,000/month. Real cost data from production testing across enterprise Azure environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Azure AI Foundry RAG with Terraform: Production-Ready Infrastructure as Code</title>
      <description>YouTube tutorials use Azure Portal clickops. Enterprises need repeatable, secure, version-controlled deployments. Here's the complete Terraform configuration for Azure AI Foundry RAG that actually works in production - with security, monitoring, and cost controls built in.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Azure Arc Multi-vCenter Implementation Guide That Actually Works</title>
      <description>Microsoft pressured us to deploy Azure Arc fast. We connected 1,200+ VMs with no strategy. Here's the complete implementation guide I wish existed before we started - covering the two-phase deployment nobody explains, the tagging strategy that prevents disasters, and why calling Finance is harder than installing agents.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $100K Problem That Resource Tags Would Have Prevented [2025 Guide]</title>
      <description>How the TYPE tag plus 5 critical tags saved $113,800 on Azure Arc patching costs. Complete 2025 Azure tagging strategy with KQL queries, PowerShell scripts, and Policy enforcement.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>