<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Chargeback Architecture: The Two Models That Actually Work</title>
      <description>Azure chargeback requires architecture-first design: subscription-per-application (clean isolation) or subscription-per-department (tag discipline required). Tags alone won't fix bad architecture. True chargeback happens in your ERP, not Azure Cost Management.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-architecture-reality</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-architecture-reality</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Modules for Azure: From Local to Published (4 Steps That Actually Work)</title>
      <description>Stop copy-pasting Terraform code across repos. Build reusable modules, version them properly, and publish to Azure DevOps Artifacts or Terraform Registry.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/terraform-modules-azure-from-local-to-published</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/terraform-modules-azure-from-local-to-published</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the CAF Won't Tell You About Azure Subscriptions (And Why Azure Arc Makes It Worse)</title>
      <description>Microsoft's Cloud Adoption Framework teaches subscriptions as a scale unit. In regulated enterprises, subscriptions are security boundaries. That's not an advanced topic—it's the foundation. Azure Arc amplifies this problem by extending broken subscription models to on-prem infrastructure.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/what-caf-wont-tell-you-azure-subscriptions-arc</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/what-caf-wont-tell-you-azure-subscriptions-arc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Policy Reality Check: Why Your Guardrails Fail After 30 Days</title>
      <description>Azure Policy is powerful on paper, but in enterprise environments the guardrails collapse almost immediately. Here's why your policies stop working and what it takes to build a policy framework that survives production.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Arc at Enterprise Scale: The Problems Microsoft Doesn't Document</title>
      <description>Azure Arc demos show 5-10 servers connecting perfectly. Enterprise deployments with hundreds of on-premises and VMware servers look different. Here's what actually breaks at scale - ghost registrations, network complexity, vCenter integration, and the operational reality Microsoft's documentation doesn't prepare you for.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-enterprise-scale-problems</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-enterprise-scale-problems</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Persistent Azure Operations Dashboard (AZQR + App Service + Storage)</title>
      <description>Microsoft's Azure Quick Review (AZQR) consolidates Advisor, Defender for Cloud, Policy, and Cost Management into one dashboard - but only runs locally. Here's how to host it in Azure App Service for 24/7 team access, scheduled scans, and historical tracking. Complete with Dockerfile, deployment scripts, and Entra ID authentication. Part 3 of the Azure Operations Platform series.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azqr-persistent-dashboard</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azqr-persistent-dashboard</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Tags for Operational Intelligence: How We Answer Executive Questions in 30 Seconds Instead of 3 Days</title>
      <description>Azure tags evolved from preventing Azure Update Manager disasters to becoming our operational intelligence layer. The Type tag excludes appliances from automated patching while enabling instant answers to executive questions about on-prem footprint, vendor inventory, and migration progress. Policy enforcement in Deny mode, tag-based filtering workflows, and KQL queries that answer 'how many machines on-prem?' in 30 seconds instead of manual 3-day inventory projects.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tags-operational-intelligence</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tags-operational-intelligence</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lie Azure Cost Management Tells Large Enterprises</title>
      <description>Azure Cost Management works beautifully—if you have perfect subscriptions or perfect tags. At enterprise scale, you have neither. Here's why Microsoft's cost tooling assumes a reality that doesn't exist, and what actually works when you're managing 40+ subscriptions with legacy chaos, M&A artifacts, and shared services everywhere.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-management-lie</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-management-lie</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can't Govern What You Can't Explain on a Napkin</title>
      <description>Azure Policy enforces rules. Landing Zones provide structure. Tags enable reporting. But if you can't explain your Azure bill on a napkin, none of it matters. Here's why governance fails—and what defensibility actually requires.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Migrate's 18-Month Data Deletion: The Enterprise Migration Timer Microsoft Calls 'Expected Behavior'</title>
      <description>Azure Migrate appliances have an 18-month hard limit before mandatory re-registration that deletes all discovery data. Microsoft documents this as 'expected behavior' in the FAQ but provides no alerts, no data preservation, and no migration path. The certificate expires at 12 months with one 6-month extension available, then forces complete appliance reconfiguration with total data loss at month 18.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-certificate-18-month-limit</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-certificate-18-month-limit</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>