<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>The New Azure Debugging Rule: When AI Says 'I Don't Know'</title>
      <description>AI has changed when you should stop debugging and open a Microsoft support ticket. If Claude can't solve your Azure problem after reading every doc, GitHub issue, and Stack Overflow post, you've hit the boundary of public knowledge. Time to use the support you're paying for.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-debugging-ai-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-debugging-ai-rule/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IP Address Management for Azure Subscription Consolidation - What Nobody Tells You About Cloud Mergers</title>
      <description>Azure native tools can't answer 'which subnet contains this IP?' across 44 subscriptions. Here's the IPAM tool I built for enterprise consolidation.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ipam-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ipam-tool/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Your Azure Scripts Break on Fresh Server 2025 (And Why Microsoft Won't Tell You)</title>
      <description>Your admin workstation still has ISE installed. Server 2025 still ships with PowerShell 5.1. Modern Azure automation needs PowerShell 7. Here's the gap nobody explains.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-scripts-break-server-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-scripts-break-server-2025/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OneNote: The Azure Admin Tool Nobody Tells You About</title>
      <description>Azure certification courses teach you Portal, CLI, and PowerShell. Nobody mentions the tool that will save you more time than all of them combined: OneNote. Here's why Send to OneNote should be muscle memory for every Azure admin.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/onenote-azure-admin-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/onenote-azure-admin-tool/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private Endpoints in Hybrid AD Environments: Why We Duplicate DNS Zones Instead of Using Forwarders</title>
      <description>Microsoft recommends DNS forwarders and Azure Private Resolver for private endpoints. We just duplicate the DNS zones in on-prem AD. Simpler architecture, clearer ownership, no shared infrastructure.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/private-endpoint-dns-hybrid-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/private-endpoint-dns-hybrid-ad/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop Reading the 1,500-Page Cloud Adoption Framework - Here's What Actually Matters</title>
      <description>Microsoft's CAF is 1,500 pages. Leadership downloads generic 'cloud skills' templates with HTML and Edge Computing. Here's what CAF actually means: 3 layers, 58 operations, zero buzzwords.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/stop-reading-caf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/stop-reading-caf/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Dashboards Are Your Cloud NOC (And Nobody Told You)</title>
      <description>New Azure admins are told to 'use workbooks' the same way students are told to 'solve for X' - without understanding what problem it solves.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboards-cloud-noc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboards-cloud-noc/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Truth About Chris Bowman's Azure Cost Dashboard</title>
      <description>Everyone links to Chris Bowman's template. Nobody explains why it's 19GB and needs Premium. Here's what's actually happening.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/chris-bowman-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/chris-bowman-dashboard/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Your Automation Fails on Fresh Azure VMs (And How I Fixed It)</title>
      <description>Three hours debugging certificate errors on fresh marketplace VMs. The culprit? Microsoft's own infrastructure serving outdated dependencies.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-vm-automation-dependency-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-vm-automation-dependency-hell/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing Azure Monitor Workbooks: Adding 200+ Services and Global Filtering</title>
      <description>How I enhanced Billy York's Azure Inventory Workbook with modern service support, global filtering, portal integration, and security hygiene monitoring for 2025 Azure environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/modernizing-azure-workbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/modernizing-azure-workbooks/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>