<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Policy Reality Check: Why Your Guardrails Fail After 30 Days</title>
      <description>Azure Policy is powerful on paper, but in enterprise environments the guardrails collapse almost immediately. Here's why your policies stop working and what it takes to build a policy framework that survives production.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can't Govern What You Can't Explain on a Napkin</title>
      <description>Azure Policy enforces rules. Landing Zones provide structure. Tags enable reporting. But if you can't explain your Azure bill on a napkin, none of it matters. Here's why governance fails—and what defensibility actually requires.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Azure Subscriptions Are Both a Security Boundary and a Billing One (And Why That Breaks Everything)</title>
      <description>Microsoft documents subscriptions as security boundaries. Finance treats them as cost centers. Nobody tells you they're both—and that this dual nature is why your Azure governance keeps failing. Here's the architectural decision that determines whether your costs will ever be defensible.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-subscriptions-security-billing-boundary</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-subscriptions-security-billing-boundary</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Policy Doesn't Fix Bad Architecture (Microsoft Pretends It Does)</title>
      <description>Azure Policy enforces rules at scale - but it can't tell you if your subscriptions make sense, if your tags are lies, or why your $2M Azure bill is indefensible. Policy is a guardrail, not a steering wheel.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-doesnt-fix-bad-architecture</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-doesnt-fix-bad-architecture</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Landing Zone Reality Check: Why Most Enterprises Drift in 90 Days</title>
      <description>Landing Zones look perfect in Microsoft's diagrams — but drift is inevitable. Here's why they fail (organizational reasons, not technical) and what must be included for Landing Zones to survive enterprise reality.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-landing-zone-reality-check</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-landing-zone-reality-check</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Hybrid Benefit vs. Cloud License: The $50K Licensing Mistake Every Azure Admin Must Avoid</title>
      <description>Azure Hybrid Benefit saves money when used correctly - but misuse triggers $50K+ compliance penalties. This is the complete operational guide for Azure administrators: pre-migration validation, audit timelines, documentation requirements, and the 8-question checklist that prevents licensing disasters.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-hybrid-benefit-complete</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-hybrid-benefit-complete</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure FinOps 2025: Complete Guide to Cloud Financial Operations</title>
      <description>Azure FinOps guide for 31,000+ resource environments: tag governance that survives 18 months, chargeback models business units accept, and cost visibility at application level (not subscription). Includes real banking industry implementation.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-finops-complete-guide</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-finops-complete-guide</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>☁️ Enterprise Migration Reality - Complete Azure Migration Guide</title>
      <description>Complete enterprise Azure migration hub - Pre-migration planning, licensing compliance, ROI reality checks, and lessons learned from real-world migrations at scale.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/migration-hub</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/migration-hub</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Admin Starter Kit (Free Download)</title>
      <description>Get everything you need to start managing Azure effectively: KQL cheat sheet, 50 Windows + 50 Linux commands, and an Azure RACI template. Free, no email required.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Command Finder (Interactive Tool)</title>
      <description>Interactive troubleshooting tool - select your Azure problem, get the exact commands to fix it. Copy-paste ready workflows for RDP issues, domain join, Group Policy, costs, and more.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-command-finder</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-command-finder</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>