<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Admin Starter Kit (Free Download)</title>
      <description>Download the Azure Admin Starter Kit: KQL cheat sheet, Windows/Linux command guides, and an Azure RACI template.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/starter-kit</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50 Linux Commands for Azure (However You Deploy)</title>
      <description>The essential Linux commands every Azure administrator needs—whether you use the Portal, PowerShell, or IaC. Includes Active Directory domain join for enterprise environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-linux-commands-azure</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-linux-commands-azure</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50 Windows Commands for Azure VMs (PowerShell + Active Directory)</title>
      <description>The essential Windows commands every Azure administrator needs—from PowerShell basics to Active Directory domain join and Group Policy troubleshooting in enterprise environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-windows-commands-azure</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/50-windows-commands-azure</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cost Optimization: What Actually Works (Not Azure Advisor Recommendations)</title>
      <description>Azure Advisor says 'right-size your VMs.' Finance says 'why is our cloud bill still increasing?' Here's what actually reduces Azure costs in production: the tactics that work when reserved instances and Advisor recommendations aren't enough.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-optimization-what-actually-works</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-optimization-what-actually-works</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Azure Role Microsoft Forgot to Certify: Why There's No Exam for Workbooks, KQL, Power BI, and AI</title>
      <description>Microsoft certifies Azure Administrators, Developers, and Data Engineers. But there's no certification for the role 80% of Azure admins actually perform: building Workbooks, writing KQL queries, creating Power BI dashboards, and leveraging AI for operations. Here's the exam that should exist.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-reporting-role-microsoft-should-create</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-reporting-role-microsoft-should-create</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Arc Ghost Registrations: Why 64% of My Arc Inventory Doesn't Exist</title>
      <description>How Azure Arc ghost registrations happen, why they wreck governance reporting, and how to detect and clean them up at scale.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-ghost-registrations</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Portal vs CLI vs PowerShell vs Bicep vs Terraform: Which One Should a Noob Learn First?</title>
      <description>Every Azure tutorial tells you what these tools do. Nobody honestly tells you which one to learn first and why. Here's the truth: start with Portal, move to CLI, then pick Bicep or Terraform. Ignore the evangelists.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tool-selection-noobs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will AI Replace Azure Administrators by 2030? An Honest Assessment from the Trenches</title>
      <description>Everyone's talking about AI replacing jobs, but nobody's written the Azure admin-specific version. Here's what happens when the person managing 40+ subscriptions explores the AI tools that might eliminate their role.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP vs Power BI AI: What Actually Creates Your Dashboards? (And What's Just Marketing)</title>
      <description>A practical comparison of MCP vs Power BI AI: what actually reads data, what actually builds visuals, and how Azure admins should think about both.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Tagging Best Practices: The $2.3M Tag Mess (247 Variations of One Tag)</title>
      <description>One tag key. 247 different spellings. $2.3M in cost allocation failures. Real lessons from enterprise Azure tag governance: why Azure Policy isn't enough and the automation that finally stopped tag chaos across 31,000 resources.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>