<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>I Spent 30 Days Testing Azure AI in a Regulated Environment. Here's What Actually Works.</title>
      <description>Microsoft says AI will revolutionize Azure operations by 2028. I tested it in October 2025 in a regulated enterprise with PCI/HIPAA requirements. 60-70% is deployable RIGHT NOW. Real ROI: Saved 15 hours/month, found $4,327 in waste, passed compliance audits easier. Here's what works, what's broken, and the 30-day roadmap.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-30-day-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-30-day-test/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Azure Tags That Make Chargeback and Showback Actually Work</title>
      <description>One tag can’t tell the whole story. Here’s how I built a practical Azure tagging model that connects operations, finance, and security — and finally made chargeback for shared services accurate and defensible.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-tags-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-tags-model/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Is Your Cell Phone (And Finance Already Understands It)</title>
      <description>Nobody asks for ROI on paying Verizon instead of building cell towers. But Finance wants ROI on Azure vs on-premises servers. The apps are the business. Azure is just the platform that runs them.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-is-your-cell-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-is-your-cell-phone/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Azure Migrate's 'Agentless' Discovery Fails in Enterprise Hybrid Environments</title>
      <description>Microsoft's official migration tool assumes single domains and flat networks. Here's why it's architecturally incompatible with multi-domain hybrid environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-enterprise-hybrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-enterprise-hybrid/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If You're Going to Azure, Better Have a Yard Sale and a Roll-Off Ready</title>
      <description>Finance celebrates retiring 100 apps instead of migrating them. Six months later: Why are we still paying for the old data center? Because 'Retire' isn't a decision, it's a $300K decommissioning project nobody budgeted for.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migration-yard-sale-rolloff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migration-yard-sale-rolloff/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finance Accepts Monthly OpEx for Phones. Why Not Cloud?</title>
      <description>Nobody questions paying Verizon instead of building cell towers. Apps on your phone = value. The network = enabler. Finance gets it. So why do they question the same model for Azure?</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/finance-accepts-monthly-opex-phones-not-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/finance-accepts-monthly-opex-phones-not-cloud/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Your Azure Migration ROI Calculation Is Wrong Before You Start</title>
      <description>Finance compares Azure VM costs to server costs and declares cloud expensive. They're missing the entire point: no VAR meetings, no hardware refresh, provision in minutes instead of months. The value isn't in the spreadsheet.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migration-roi-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migration-roi-wrong/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If You Can't Code Your Architecture, You're Not an Architect</title>
      <description>Deploy one VM to learn the variables. Deploy three VMs to learn you're wasting time. Code your fourth deployment or admit you're just clicking buttons for a living.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/if-you-cant-code-your-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/if-you-cant-code-your-architecture/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Reverse-Engineered a Power BI Dashboard (PBIX Modernizer Tool)</title>
      <description>Chris Bowman's CCO Dashboard is 200+ pages of Power BI. I needed to understand it to build CCO 2.0. Built a tool that extracts all queries, measures, and relationships in seconds. .pbix files are just ZIP archives.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/pbix-modernizer-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/pbix-modernizer-tool/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extract KQL Queries from Azure Workbooks (Workbook → App Tool)</title>
      <description>Azure Workbooks hide 110+ items and complex KQL queries in nested JSON. Built a Streamlit tool that extracts everything in seconds. Parsed Billy York's workbook: 41 queries, full structure, exportable. No more clicking through Azure Portal.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/workbook-app-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/workbook-app-tool/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>