<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>The Azure Audit Gap Nobody Talks About: Why Your 90-Day Logs Won't Survive a 7-Year Audit</title>
      <description>Most Azure environments are silently non-compliant with regulatory audit requirements. Here's the three-part problem everyone faces, how app registrations create blind spots, and the architecture to fix it before your next audit.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-audit-gap-nobody-talks-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-audit-gap-nobody-talks-about/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I'm Not Renewing My Azure Certifications. Here's Why I'm Getting AI-102 Instead.</title>
      <description>I earned AZ-103, AZ-303, and AZ-304 in 2020. Microsoft wants me to renew them. I'm not renewing. I'm investing those 100 hours in AI-102 instead. Here's the data behind that decision.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/not-renewing-azure-certs-choosing-ai-102/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/not-renewing-azure-certs-choosing-ai-102/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happens When You Open an Azure Support Ticket: Inside the Enterprise Support Model</title>
      <description>Understanding Microsoft's global support organization helps you navigate it effectively. Here's what actually happens when you click 'Submit Ticket' - from TAM metrics to contractor handoffs to backend access.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-support-ticket-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-support-ticket-reality/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The KQL Problem Nobody Warns You About: You're Learning One Language Across Five Different Systems</title>
      <description>Everyone learns KQL in Log Analytics. Nobody warns you about Resource Graph, Sentinel, App Insights, or Defender. Here's the decision framework you need before you build the wrong thing in the wrong place.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/kql-multiple-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/kql-multiple-systems/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Spent 30 Days Testing Azure AI in a Regulated Environment. Here's What Actually Works.</title>
      <description>Microsoft says AI will revolutionize Azure operations by 2028. I tested it in October 2025 in a regulated enterprise with PCI/HIPAA requirements. 60-70% is deployable RIGHT NOW. Real ROI: Saved 15 hours/month, found $4,327 in waste, passed compliance audits easier. Here's what works, what's broken, and the 30-day roadmap.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-30-day-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-30-day-test/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Azure Tags That Make Chargeback and Showback Actually Work</title>
      <description>One tag can’t tell the whole story. Here’s how I built a practical Azure tagging model that connects operations, finance, and security — and finally made chargeback for shared services accurate and defensible.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-tags-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-tags-model/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Is Your Cell Phone (And Finance Already Understands It)</title>
      <description>Nobody asks for ROI on paying Verizon instead of building cell towers. But Finance wants ROI on Azure vs on-premises servers. The apps are the business. Azure is just the platform that runs them.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-is-your-cell-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-is-your-cell-phone/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Azure Migrate's 'Agentless' Discovery Fails in Enterprise Hybrid Environments</title>
      <description>Microsoft's official migration tool assumes single domains and flat networks. Here's why it's architecturally incompatible with multi-domain hybrid environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-enterprise-hybrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-enterprise-hybrid/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If You're Going to Azure, Better Have a Yard Sale and a Roll-Off Ready</title>
      <description>Finance celebrates retiring 100 apps instead of migrating them. Six months later: Why are we still paying for the old data center? Because 'Retire' isn't a decision, it's a $300K decommissioning project nobody budgeted for.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migration-yard-sale-rolloff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migration-yard-sale-rolloff/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finance Accepts Monthly OpEx for Phones. Why Not Cloud?</title>
      <description>Nobody questions paying Verizon instead of building cell towers. Apps on your phone = value. The network = enabler. Finance gets it. So why do they question the same model for Azure?</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/finance-accepts-monthly-opex-phones-not-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/finance-accepts-monthly-opex-phones-not-cloud/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>