<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Will AI Replace Azure Administrators by 2030? An Honest Assessment from the Trenches</title>
      <description>Everyone's talking about AI replacing jobs, but nobody's written the Azure admin-specific version. Here's what happens when the person managing 40+ subscriptions explores the AI tools that might eliminate their role.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/will-ai-replace-azure-administrators-by-2030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MCP vs Power BI AI: What Actually Creates Your Dashboards? (And What's Just Marketing)</title>
      <description>Microsoft is throwing AI buzzwords everywhere. Power BI Copilot, MCP, AI-powered insights, Fabric with AI. I spent 10 weeks modernizing dashboards with AI. Here's what actually creates visuals vs what just accesses data—and why Azure admins are confused.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/mcp-vs-powerbi-ai-what-actually-creates-dashboards</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $2.3M Tag Mess: What Happens When 78002566 Becomes 247 Different Variations</title>
      <description>CFO asked for Azure costs by department. I found 247 different variations of the same cost center tag. 'Production' spelled 12 ways. Application names in chaos. Here's the tag governance policy that fixed it - and the template you can deploy today.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tag-governance-247-variations</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an Azure Arc Lab with Private Link (No Public IPs)</title>
      <description>Deploy a production-realistic Azure Arc demo environment using Private Link for secure hybrid management. Complete Terraform code included - because your CISO won't approve the public internet version.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-private-lab</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI Pricing 2025: Real Costs After Spending $500 on Testing</title>
      <description>Real Azure OpenAI pricing breakdown: GPT-4 costs $0.03/1K tokens but hidden hosting fees ($1,224/month), PTU pricing, and infrastructure charges turn $50 pilots into $2,000 monthly bills. Actual cost data from testing across 44 Azure subscriptions.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-openai-pricing-real-costs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Azure AI Foundry RAG with Terraform: Production-Ready Infrastructure as Code</title>
      <description>YouTube tutorials use Azure Portal clickops. Enterprises need repeatable, secure, version-controlled deployments. Here's the complete Terraform configuration for Azure AI Foundry RAG that actually works in production - with security, monitoring, and cost controls built in.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-terraform</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Azure Arc Multi-vCenter Implementation Guide That Actually Works</title>
      <description>Microsoft pressured us to deploy Azure Arc fast. We connected 1,200+ VMs with no strategy. Here's the complete implementation guide I wish existed before we started - covering the two-phase deployment nobody explains, the tagging strategy that prevents disasters, and why calling Finance is harder than installing agents.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-arc-vcenter-implementation-guide</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $100K Problem That Resource Tags Would Have Prevented [2025 Guide]</title>
      <description>How the TYPE tag plus 5 critical tags saved $113,800 on Azure Arc patching costs. Complete 2025 Azure tagging strategy with KQL queries, PowerShell scripts, and Policy enforcement.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/resource-tags-100k-problem</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server 2025 Vector Database: What Microsoft Doesn't Tell You About Production Deployments</title>
      <description>Microsoft integrated vector databases into SQL Server 2025. The docs show you how to enable it. They don't show you what happens when you store 10 million vectors, run 100K queries per day, or why your $500/month SQL Server becomes $3,000/month.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sql-server-2025-vector-database-production-reality</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sql-server-2025-vector-database-production-reality</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure AI Foundry RAG: The Enterprise Reality Check Nobody Gives You</title>
      <description>YouTube tutorials show you how to build RAG with Azure AI Foundry in 20 minutes. They don't show you the $3,000/year cost, the production failures, or when you shouldn't use it at all. Here's what happens when you actually deploy this at scale.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-rag-enterprise-reality</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-foundry-rag-enterprise-reality</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>