<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Policy Reality Check: Why Your Guardrails Fail After 30 Days</title>
      <description>Azure Policy is powerful on paper, but in enterprise environments the guardrails collapse almost immediately. Here's why your policies stop working and what it takes to build a policy framework that survives production.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-reality-check</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Tags for Operational Intelligence: How We Answer Executive Questions in 30 Seconds Instead of 3 Days</title>
      <description>Azure tags evolved from preventing Azure Update Manager disasters to becoming our operational intelligence layer. The Type tag excludes appliances from automated patching while enabling instant answers to executive questions about on-prem footprint, vendor inventory, and migration progress. Policy enforcement in Deny mode, tag-based filtering workflows, and KQL queries that answer 'how many machines on-prem?' in 30 seconds instead of manual 3-day inventory projects.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tags-operational-intelligence</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-tags-operational-intelligence</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lie Azure Cost Management Tells Large Enterprises</title>
      <description>Azure Cost Management works beautifully—if you have perfect subscriptions or perfect tags. At enterprise scale, you have neither. Here's why Microsoft's cost tooling assumes a reality that doesn't exist, and what actually works when you're managing 40+ subscriptions with legacy chaos, M&A artifacts, and shared services everywhere.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-management-lie</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-management-lie</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can't Govern What You Can't Explain on a Napkin</title>
      <description>Azure Policy enforces rules. Landing Zones provide structure. Tags enable reporting. But if you can't explain your Azure bill on a napkin, none of it matters. Here's why governance fails—and what defensibility actually requires.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-governance-napkin-test</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Migrate's 18-Month Data Deletion: The Enterprise Migration Timer Microsoft Calls 'Expected Behavior'</title>
      <description>Azure Migrate appliances have an 18-month hard limit before mandatory re-registration that deletes all discovery data. Microsoft documents this as 'expected behavior' in the FAQ but provides no alerts, no data preservation, and no migration path. The certificate expires at 12 months with one 6-month extension available, then forces complete appliance reconfiguration with total data loss at month 18.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-certificate-18-month-limit</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migrate-certificate-18-month-limit</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Azure Subscriptions Are Both a Security Boundary and a Billing One (And Why That Breaks Everything)</title>
      <description>Microsoft documents subscriptions as security boundaries. Finance treats them as cost centers. Nobody tells you they're both—and that this dual nature is why your Azure governance keeps failing. Here's the architectural decision that determines whether your costs will ever be defensible.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-subscriptions-security-billing-boundary</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-subscriptions-security-billing-boundary</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Logic App That Monitors Every Expiring Certificate in Azure (And Accidentally Saved Our Migration)</title>
      <description>Production Logic App that monitors app registration certificates and secrets via Microsoft Graph API. Handles pagination for 100+ apps, extracts owner information, sends HTML email alerts. Built for security compliance, caught Azure Migrate appliances expiring before production migration. Complete walkthrough with working code.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/logic-app-certificate-monitor</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/logic-app-certificate-monitor</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Azure Tags Fail at Scale (And Always Will)</title>
      <description>Tags work beautifully at 100 resources. At 10,000 resources, they're a source of organizational fiction. Here's why tag-based governance always collapses—not because people are careless, but because tags require human perfection that doesn't exist at enterprise scale.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/why-azure-tags-fail-at-scale</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/why-azure-tags-fail-at-scale</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Policy Doesn't Fix Bad Architecture (Microsoft Pretends It Does)</title>
      <description>Azure Policy enforces rules at scale - but it can't tell you if your subscriptions make sense, if your tags are lies, or why your $2M Azure bill is indefensible. Policy is a guardrail, not a steering wheel.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-doesnt-fix-bad-architecture</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-policy-doesnt-fix-bad-architecture</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Landing Zone Reality Check: Why Most Enterprises Drift in 90 Days</title>
      <description>Landing Zones look perfect in Microsoft's diagrams — but drift is inevitable. Here's why they fail (organizational reasons, not technical) and what must be included for Landing Zones to survive enterprise reality.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-landing-zone-reality-check</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-landing-zone-reality-check</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>