<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Gartner’s AI Forecast for 2030: What It Really Means for Azure Admins</title>
      <description>Gartner predicts that by 2030, 0% of IT work will be done without AI involvement. Here’s what that means for Azure administrators, cloud engineers, and anyone responsible for running enterprise cloud environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/gartner-ai-forecast-azure-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/gartner-ai-forecast-azure-admin/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Admin: Stop Being a Human API Wrapper</title>
      <description>Traditional Azure administration is becoming AI-assisted automation. Here's how to position yourself as an AI Admin instead of a human ticket processor - whether you're managing 40,000 resources or bootstrapping your first deployment.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/the-ai-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/the-ai-admin/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Companies Don't Want Azure Admins Anymore. They Want People Who Can Make AI Work. (And Almost Nobody Is Teaching This)</title>
      <description>I searched 'Azure Administrator skills 2025' and found hundreds of articles. Not one mentioned AI capability. Meanwhile, ChatGPT just wrote better PowerShell than half my team in 30 seconds. The gap between what's being taught and what companies need is massive.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/ai-azure-admins-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/ai-azure-admins-gap/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Three AI Operations Roles That Don't Exist Yet (But Will in 12 Months)</title>
      <description>Search for 'AI operations governance jobs' and find nothing. Meanwhile someone has to monitor AI usage, prevent security disasters, and measure ROI. These three roles don't exist officially. They will soon.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/three-ai-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/three-ai-roles/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Chaos to Enterprise: How I Set Up Terraform Remote State in Azure (And Why You Need This Yesterday)</title>
      <description>After our third 'who deleted the state file' incident, I finally set up proper Terraform remote state. 30 minutes of work eliminated an entire category of disasters. Here's exactly how to do it, with zero fluff.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/terraform-remote-state-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/terraform-remote-state-azure/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Application Migration Checklist Nobody Gave You (And Why Your Migrations Keep Failing)</title>
      <description>Microsoft's migration docs won't tell you this: 80% of migration failures happen because you didn't ask these 8 questions BEFORE you started. Here's the checklist that actually works in enterprise environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/application-migration-checklist-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/application-migration-checklist-azure/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Spreadsheet I Wish I Had in 2019: Before You Migrate Anything to Azure</title>
      <description>In 2019, leadership said 'we're going to the cloud.' Nobody asked how many applications we had. That one question would have saved millions. Here's the spreadsheet that forces the conversation before you start migrating.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cloud-migration-reality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/cloud-migration-reality-check/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only 1% of Azure Admins Know These Three Tools — And Even Fewer Know When to Use Which</title>
      <description>I passed AZ-104. I was certified. I knew how to create VMs, configure networking, deploy ARM templates. Day 1 on the job: 'Pull me an inventory.' AZ-104 never covered this. Here's the certification gap nobody talks about, the query that proves it, and the templates that save your career.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/only-1-percent-know-these-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/only-1-percent-know-these-tools/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I'll Pull The Meta From ARM - What 6 Months of KQL Actually Looks Like</title>
      <description>I promised executives I'd query Azure Resource Manager for 'the answers.' They nodded. I got budget. Nobody asked what metadata actually exists in ARM. Here's the 35-line query I built to answer 'what VMs do we have' - and the 35 more I needed for everything else.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/pull-meta-from-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/pull-meta-from-arm/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buzzwords, Technical Terms, and the Meetings Where Nobody Understands Anything</title>
      <description>Why corporate arrogance kills more cloud projects than technical complexity ever could. The uncomfortable truth about how leadership uses business buzzwords and technical teams use jargon - and nobody admits they don't understand each other.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/buzzwords-meetings-confusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/buzzwords-meetings-confusion/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>