<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Stop Losing Your KQL Queries: The Git-Based Query Library Nobody Told You About</title>
      <description>You've written the perfect KQL query. Three months later, you can't find it. Here's the simple Git workflow that saves me 10+ hours a month searching for queries I already wrote.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/kql-query-library-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/kql-query-library-git/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Missing SOC 2 Guide: Azure Activity Log Setup (Grill Assembly Manual Edition)</title>
      <description>Every guide says 'configure diagnostic settings.' Nobody shows you which button to click. Here's the step-by-step tutorial that actually works, written for someone who's never done this before.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/soc2-activity-log-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/soc2-activity-log-step-by-step/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOC 2 Audit Prep Part 2: Azure AD Audit Log Retention Setup (Step-by-Step)</title>
      <description>The grill assembly manual for capturing Azure AD audit logs - app registrations, consent grants, sign-ins, and role assignments. Every click, every command, every verification. Part 2 of fixing the 90-day audit gap.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/soc2-azure-ad-audit-logs-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/soc2-azure-ad-audit-logs-step-by-step/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Found .NET 6 on 47 VMs. Now I'm Supposed to Remove It. Here's Why That's Impossible.</title>
      <description>Tenable finds a vulnerability. Security creates a ticket. Change management wants approval. App teams say not my problem. Infrastructure doesn't own the apps. Welcome to the operational reality nobody talks about.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tenable-says-remove-dotnet6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/tenable-says-remove-dotnet6/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Azure Audit Gap Nobody Talks About: Why Your 90-Day Logs Won't Survive a 7-Year Audit</title>
      <description>Most Azure environments are silently non-compliant with regulatory audit requirements. Here's the three-part problem everyone faces, how app registrations create blind spots, and the architecture to fix it before your next audit.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-audit-gap-nobody-talks-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-audit-gap-nobody-talks-about/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I'm Not Renewing My Azure Certifications. Here's Why I'm Getting AI-102 Instead.</title>
      <description>I earned AZ-103, AZ-303, and AZ-304 in 2020. Microsoft wants me to renew them. I'm not renewing. I'm investing those 100 hours in AI-102 instead. Here's the data behind that decision.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/not-renewing-azure-certs-choosing-ai-102/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/not-renewing-azure-certs-choosing-ai-102/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happens When You Open an Azure Support Ticket: Inside the Enterprise Support Model</title>
      <description>Understanding Microsoft's global support organization helps you navigate it effectively. Here's what actually happens when you click 'Submit Ticket' - from TAM metrics to contractor handoffs to backend access.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-support-ticket-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-support-ticket-reality/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The KQL Problem Nobody Warns You About: You're Learning One Language Across Five Different Systems</title>
      <description>Everyone learns KQL in Log Analytics. Nobody warns you about Resource Graph, Sentinel, App Insights, or Defender. Here's the decision framework you need before you build the wrong thing in the wrong place.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/kql-multiple-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/kql-multiple-systems/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Spent 30 Days Testing Azure AI in a Regulated Environment. Here's What Actually Works.</title>
      <description>Microsoft says AI will revolutionize Azure operations by 2028. I tested it in October 2025 in a regulated enterprise with PCI/HIPAA requirements. 60-70% is deployable RIGHT NOW. Real ROI: Saved 15 hours/month, found $4,327 in waste, passed compliance audits easier. Here's what works, what's broken, and the 30-day roadmap.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-30-day-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ai-30-day-test/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Azure Tags That Make Chargeback and Showback Actually Work</title>
      <description>One tag can’t tell the whole story. Here’s how I built a practical Azure tagging model that connects operations, finance, and security — and finally made chargeback for shared services accurate and defensible.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-tags-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-chargeback-tags-model/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>