<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Is Your Cell Phone (And Finance Already Understands It)</title>
      <description>Nobody asks for ROI on paying Verizon instead of building cell towers. But Finance wants ROI on Azure vs on-premises servers. The apps are the business. Azure is just the platform that runs them.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-is-your-cell-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-is-your-cell-phone/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finance Accepts Monthly OpEx for Phones. Why Not Cloud?</title>
      <description>Nobody questions paying Verizon instead of building cell towers. Apps on your phone = value. The network = enabler. Finance gets it. So why do they question the same model for Azure?</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/finance-accepts-monthly-opex-phones-not-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/finance-accepts-monthly-opex-phones-not-cloud/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Your Azure Migration ROI Calculation Is Wrong Before You Start</title>
      <description>Finance compares Azure VM costs to server costs and declares cloud expensive. They're missing the entire point: no VAR meetings, no hardware refresh, provision in minutes instead of months. The value isn't in the spreadsheet.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migration-roi-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-migration-roi-wrong/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If You Can't Code Your Architecture, You're Not an Architect</title>
      <description>Deploy one VM to learn the variables. Deploy three VMs to learn you're wasting time. Code your fourth deployment or admit you're just clicking buttons for a living.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/if-you-cant-code-your-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/if-you-cant-code-your-architecture/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Reverse-Engineered a Power BI Dashboard (PBIX Modernizer Tool)</title>
      <description>Chris Bowman's CCO Dashboard is 200+ pages of Power BI. I needed to understand it to build CCO 2.0. Built a tool that extracts all queries, measures, and relationships in seconds. .pbix files are just ZIP archives.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/pbix-modernizer-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/pbix-modernizer-tool/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extract KQL Queries from Azure Workbooks (Workbook → App Tool)</title>
      <description>Azure Workbooks hide 110+ items and complex KQL queries in nested JSON. Built a Streamlit tool that extracts everything in seconds. Parsed Billy York's workbook: 41 queries, full structure, exportable. No more clicking through Azure Portal.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/workbook-app-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/workbook-app-tool/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your CMDB Is Wrong (And Cloud Migration Fixes It)</title>
      <description>I spent 3 months bridging the gap between ServiceNow records with no context, RVtools exports mixing servers with virtual desktops, and ManageEngine tracking 21 AD domains. Then Azure Resource Graph gave me 31,000 accurate, tagged resources in 30 seconds.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cmdb-wrong-cloud-fixes-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cmdb-wrong-cloud-fixes-it/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Azure Costs: Start with Apps, Not Subscriptions</title>
      <description>Microsoft says subscriptions are billing boundaries. Two years later you're maintaining manual spreadsheets. Here's what nobody tells you: count your applications first, then design subscriptions around teams.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-costs-apps-not-subscriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-costs-apps-not-subscriptions/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Azure Console Button Is a Lie (And You Don't Need AMA)</title>
      <description>VMware admins: That 'Connect' button isn't console access. Serial Console is hidden in Help > Boot Diagnostics, works without networking, and doesn't require Azure Monitor Agent. Here's what Microsoft didn't tell you.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-console-button-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-console-button-lie/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCCM, WSUS, Azure Update Manager, Intune: Which One Do I Actually Use?</title>
      <description>Three Microsoft reps gave me three different answers about patching Azure VMs. Here's what each tool actually does, which workloads need which tool, and why you need multiple tools during enterprise migration. The decision matrix Microsoft won't publish.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sccm-wsus-azure-update-manager-intune-confusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/sccm-wsus-azure-update-manager-intune-confusion/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>