<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Noob</title>
    <description>Don't be a Noob</description>
    <link>https://azure-noob.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>IP Address Management for Azure Subscription Consolidation - What Nobody Tells You About Cloud Mergers</title>
      <description>Azure native tools can't answer 'which subnet contains this IP?' across 44 subscriptions. Here's the IPAM tool I built for enterprise consolidation.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ipam-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-ipam-tool/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Dashboards Are Your Cloud NOC (And Nobody Told You)</title>
      <description>New Azure admins are told to 'use workbooks' the same way students are told to 'solve for X' - without understanding what problem it solves.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboards-cloud-noc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-dashboards-cloud-noc/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Truth About Chris Bowman's Azure Cost Dashboard</title>
      <description>Everyone links to Chris Bowman's template. Nobody explains why it's 19GB and needs Premium. Here's what's actually happening.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/chris-bowman-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/chris-bowman-dashboard/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Your Automation Fails on Fresh Azure VMs (And How I Fixed It)</title>
      <description>Three hours debugging certificate errors on fresh marketplace VMs. The culprit? Microsoft's own infrastructure serving outdated dependencies.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-vm-automation-dependency-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-vm-automation-dependency-hell/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing Azure Monitor Workbooks: Adding 200+ Services and Global Filtering</title>
      <description>How I enhanced Billy York's Azure Inventory Workbook with modern service support, global filtering, portal integration, and security hygiene monitoring for 2025 Azure environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/modernizing-azure-workbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/modernizing-azure-workbooks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Your Azure Cost Reports Don't Match Your Business Reality</title>
      <description>Azure Cost Management works perfectly. Your finance team still can't figure out who should pay for what. Here's why cost center tagging doesn't solve enterprise chargeback.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-reports-business-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-cost-reports-business-reality/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure Update Manager Reality Check: Why 77% of Your VMs Are Unsupported</title>
      <description>Opened Azure Update Manager and saw 1,791 VMs that need updates? Here's the uncomfortable truth about what that number really means and the KQL queries to find your real target.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-update-manager-reality-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-update-manager-reality-check/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Most Azure Migrations Fail: The Institutional Knowledge Problem</title>
      <description>Azure Migrate works perfectly. The problem is no one remembers how their applications actually work. Here's why enterprise migrations fail before they start.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/why-most-azure-migrations-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/why-most-azure-migrations-fail/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Wish I Knew About Azure Resource Tags</title>
      <description>Order, capitalization, spelling, and the Type tag that will save your sanity. Hard-earned lessons from real Azure environments.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-resource-tags-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-resource-tags-guide/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Raw Data to Actionable Insights: Mastering Azure VM Inventory with KQL</title>
      <description>Build a single KQL query that inventories every VM, cleans up OS details, and assigns the right patching workflow—Intune, Azure Update Manager, or Linux package managers.</description>
      <link>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-vm-inventory-kql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure-noob.com/blog/azure-vm-inventory-kql/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>